Guide to the Records of the University Christian Foundation RG.39.3
New York University Archives
Records of the University Christian Foundation
1906-1980
New York University Archives
University Christian Foundation
RG.39.3
11 Linear Feet (27 manuscript boxes)
The University Christian Foundation was a Protestant outreach organization that operated on the Washington Square Campus from 1906 to 1977. Oficially founded on October 24, 1906, as the Students' Club of the Young Men's Christian Association, the organization was later renamed the University Christian Association in 1927 before finally becoming the University Christian Foundation in 1961. The bulk of records date from 1954 to 1972 and reflect the organization's activities under its various guises.
Separated Material
Unidentified photographs, slides and negatives of various dates have been separated to the Photograph Collection.
Related Material at the New York University Archives
Records of the Interfaith Council of Washington Square College, 1948-1947.
Arrangement
The records are organized into six series, one of which is further subdivided into two subseries. Materials within these series and subseries are arranged chronologically.
Series List
Christian Association
University Christian Foundation
Ecumenical Foundation
James B. Harrison, Chaplain
Interfaith Council
Programs
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of minutes, correspondence, religious census reports, annual reports, memoranda, agendas, announcements, proposals, financial statements, pamphlets, brochures, calendars, working papers, surveys, speeches, constitutions, bylaws, and ephemera.
History of the University Christian Foundation
The University Christian Foundation began as a Protestant outreach organization in the early years of the twentieth century. Officially founded on October 24, 1906, as the Student's Club of the Young Men's Christian Association, the organization's stated purpose was "to promote and maintain the highest standard of religious, moral, social and intellectual life" on New York University's Washington Square campus. It offered weekly Bible study classes, organized informal dinners to which guest speakers were invited, and rented out the gymnasium at Judson Memorial Church on Washington Square South for its members' use.
In the autumn of 1927, the Students' Club was renamed to the University Christian Association and reorganized to include women. The organization continued to offer Bible study classes, hold meetings and organize socials for its members. A freshman camp was also instituted at this time to help incoming students bridge the gap between high school and college. The Association was housed on two floors at 26 Washington Place for some time, but eventually moved to Judson Memorial Church on Washington Square South. In 1939 the Association moved once more to newly renovated offices at 2 Washington Square North, which it shared with the Roman Catholic Newman Club and the Jewish Society, a precursor of the Jewish Cultural Foundation. The new headquarters consisted of three offices, a shared lounge and a large common kitchen. Custodial care was provided by NYU.
Reevaluation of the organization by the National Council of Churches in the late 1950s resulted in the creation of the University Christian Foundation in 1961. Although the original mission of the religoius organization remained largely unchanged, a greater focus was placed on secular considerations. Advancement of the civil rights movement in the United States and escalation of the war in Vietnam had a great effect on the organization and its activities. Three full-tine chaplains were hired to counsel UCF members not only in matters of faith, but also on the draft, involvement in anti-war protests, civil rights on campus, and reproductive rights of women. The UCF also established at this time the first dormitory on Washington Square campus to admit Asian and African-American students.
During this decade, national support of local campus ministries began to wane, and staffing was cut drastically. By 1972 the UCF had no full-time chaplain; services were administered by volunteers and part-time seminary students. In 1975 Pamela Bolen was appointed lay executive director of the organization. Under Bolen's direction, the organization became more involved in global issues and campaigns, including those led by the World Hunger Coalition, the United Farm Workers Association and black South Africans struggling to end apartheid. In August of 1976, the UCF and its Women's Center were moved by the University to 21 Washington Place, Room 802. The Board of Directors voted to suspend operations of the UCF on November 30, 1977, due to a lack of funding and drop in student participation. The corporation was kept alive for future student needs, but the Board held its last annual meeting in the Spring of 1977.
The Interfaith Council was a faculty-staff body maintaining correspondence among the campus ministries of Catholics, Jews, and Protestants. Its predecessor, the Interfaith Committee, oversaw the ministries' shared quarters at 2 Washington Square North in the 1940s and 1950s. In 1967 the Council of the University proposed the establishment of a Committee on Faith and Life at NYU under the Office of Student Affairs, and relieved the Interfaith Committee of its responsibility as a standing committee of the University. Reference is made to the Interfaith Committee and Interfaith Council throughout the UCF collection. The Ecumenical Foundation, another organization referred to in this collection, was organized in the late 1960s by several national church organizations to support campus ministries with staff, programs and funding. Its connection with the UCF lasted only a few years; the UCF severing ties in 1974. OASIS, Overseas & American Students' International Society, succeeded the YMCA and UCF in providing outreach to NYU's foreign students. Material concerning OASIS can also be found among the UCF collection.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Provenance
The records of the UCF were transfered to the University Archives on October 11, 1978 and November 18, 1982, by the UCF's Executive Director, Pamela Bolen.
Bylaws (administrative records); Bulletins.; Announcements.; Agendas (administrative records); Financial statements.; Printed ephemera.; Pamphlets.; Reports.; Women's rights -- United States -- 20th century; Civil rights movements -- United States.; Protest movements -- United States.; Birth control -- United States.; Memorandums.; Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; Records surveys.; Brewster, Kingman, 1882-1957; Bolen, Pamela; Dunbar, Rosalie E., 1947-; Dondore, Constance; Hanson, John; Ecumenical Foundation of New York University; Leslie, Charles; Harrison, James B.; McCloskey, Jeannie; Maggin, Jane; Rogge, David F.; New York University; New York University. Medical Center; YMCA; YWCA
- Series 1: Christian Association
  - Christian Association History, 1906-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    3 1142 04225019 4
  - YMCA University Heights, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C.A. History, 1932-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Surverys, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Board Personnel Committee, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Board, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Board Minutes, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report of the Director, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee on the Evaluation of C. A. Work, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - C.A. General, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - C.A. General, 1906-1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C.A. Survey at Washington Square, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lutheran Proposal for Coordination with C.A., 1932-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225020 2
  - Vernon Bodein, Director, 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Advisory Board, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Freshman Camp, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - C.A. Self-Survey, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Self-Survey, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Historical Documents, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Survey by Natl. Council of Churches, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Study, Proposed Protestant Ministry, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Information, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Information, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series 2: University Christian Foundation
  - Subseries 1: General materials
    - U.C.F. Constitution, brochures Correspondence, Craig S. Barlette, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225021 0
    - U.C.F. funding, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Secretary's Annual Report, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - UCF Constitution, by-laws, ca.1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Perkins and Will, architect's report, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - U.C.F. Publicity, ca.1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - C.A. and U.C.F. at NYU, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Staff reports, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225022 8
    - Signatories, minutes, corr., 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Description of U.C.F., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Budget, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Board/staff meetings, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Signatory, proxy letters, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Programming, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Staff report, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, executive meetings, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - National Council of Churches, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, reports, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, reports, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, reports, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Staff reports, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225023 6
    - Correspondence, Board, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Development Committee minutes, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - U.C.F. at NYU, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Development Committee minutes, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - U.C.F. Board Minutes, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - U.C.F. at NYU, notebook, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - U.C.F at NYU, notebook, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Committee on Review, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Board minutes, corr., reports, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225024 4
    - Staff meetings, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Board meetings, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hanson, John, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hanson, John, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hanson, John, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Hanson, John, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - LOC Minutes (Local Operating Council for the Ministry), 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225025 1
    - LOC Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - U.C.F. at NYU, office copy, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - U.C.F. at NYU, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - U.C.F. at NYU, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Annual Board Meeting, Apr 3, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - NYU Survey, National Council of Churches, 1957-1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - [Activities], 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - [Activities], 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Minutes and Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225026 9
    - Advisory Board Minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Board Minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Board, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, Board, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, Board, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Minutes and Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Staff Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Minutes and reports, Board and staff, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225027 7
    - Minutes and reports, Board and staff, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Minutes and reports, Board and staff, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, Board, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Minutes and correspondence, Board, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - U.C.F, 71-75, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, Board, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - College Ministries, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Kosher kitchen, 1972-1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, Board, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225028 5
    - Minutes, Board, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, Board, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, Board, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Funding requests, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Publicity, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225029 3
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, Board, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Newsletter, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Reports, Treasurer's, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225030 1
    - Executive Committee Notes, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Retreat, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - U.C.F. Activities, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Bolen, Pamela, personal file, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Minutes, Board of Directors, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - UCF Activities, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225031 9
    - Suspension of activities, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - U.C.F. Board, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - UCF Board, 1979-80, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - UCF Archives, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - UCF brochures, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - UCF letterhead, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Faculty Finance Drive and Financial Records
    - Faculty finance drive, 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225032 7
    - Faculty finance drive, 1955-1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Faculty finance drive, 1959-1961 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Faculty finance drive, Friends, 1961-1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Faculty finance drive, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Faculty finance drive, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Faculty finance drive, sample letters, 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Parent contributions, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225033 5
    - Parent contributions, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Parent contributions, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Contributions, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Sample finance letters, 1959-1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Ledger sheets, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Income tax, 1964-1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Financial reports, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225034 3
    - Financial statements, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Financial statements, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Financial statements, 1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Financial records, ASSABC, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Foundations and funding, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Finances, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - New York City churches, A-E, 1953-1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - New York City churches, F-J, 1953-1972 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - New York City churches, M-T, 1953-1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - New York City churches, local, 1953-1972 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - New York City churches, non-local, 1953-1972 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Series 3: Ecumenical Foundation
  - Ecumenical Foundation, 1965-1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225035 0
  - Ecumenical Foundation, strategy committee, 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Ecumenical Foundation, staff council, 1966-1968 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Ecumenical Foundation, staff council, 1966-1968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Ecumenical Foundation, 1966-1968 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Ecumenical Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Ecumenical Foundation, 1968-1972 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Ecumenical Foundation, finances and budget, 1969-1972 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Series 4: James B. Harrison, Chaplain
  - Aggression, conference on, Jul 1967 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225036 8
  - Church & Higher Education Projects, Apr 1969 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Civil Liberties (regulation of hairstyles, Nov 1966 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Civil Rights (Martin Luther King, Jr.), Apr 1968-May-68 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, NYU, 1964-1967 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Columbia University, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Discipline (Re: disruption of Placement Office), 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Cooper Union, Nov 1967 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, NYU, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Caucus (re: SDS (Students for a Democratic Society)), 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Committee on War and Peace, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Committee on War and Peace, 1966-1967 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Faculty-Student Dialog, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225037 6
  - Hageman Project (Council for an International Ministry), 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - International Ministry Task Group, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Center for International Studies, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Marxism, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Military Research at NYU, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Newsletter, All-Square Student Affairs, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - OASIS (Overseas & American Students' International Society), 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Orthodox Fellowship, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Play, "The Changing Grass", 1967 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Resistance, Draft, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Staff meetings, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - SCENE (newsletter), 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Student attitudes, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Student Christian Movement, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225038 4
  - Student Pentecostal Fellowship, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Student Presidents' Conference, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Student Strike (Afro-American Center), Oct 1968 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), 1966-1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Teaching the New Student, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Teach-in (Viet-Nam), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Tillich, Monsignor Ivan, Oct 1967 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Universities Committee on War and Peace, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Universities Committee on War and Peace, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Universities Committee on War and Peace, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Universities Committee on War and Peace, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Voice (Student party), 1967 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - West Side Discussion Group, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225039 2
  - Witherspoon, John, Society (Religion and the homosexual), 1966 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - World Student Christian Federation, 1957-1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Worship, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Series 5: Interfaith Council
  - Interfaith Council, 1957-1959 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225040 0
  - Interfaith Council, 1960-1965 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Interfaith Council Archives, [1962-1969] (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Interfaith Council, 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Interfaith Council Film Benefit, 1966-1967 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Interfaith Council, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Interfaith Council, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Interfaith Council, University Heights, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Series 6: Programs
  - ABM (Anti-ballistic missile), 1969 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225041 8
  - Afro-American Center, 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Art/Exhibits, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Baptists, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Baha'i Club, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Birth Control, Overpopulation Committee, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Birth Control Clinic Proposal, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Birth Control Clinic, 1970-1972 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Birth Control (University Health Service), 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Celebration-M.L.K., Jr., agape eucharist, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Committee to End the War, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Convocation (founding of U.C.F.), May 9, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - David, Christopher L., 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Death and Dying Series, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Depth (Third World Discussion Group), 1967 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225042 6
  - Draft Counselling, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Draft Counselling, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Drug Counselling, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Education, School of, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Crisis, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Environment-Earth Day, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Program, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Teach-in, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Faculty luncheons, 1949-1961 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225043 4
  - Faculty luncheons, 1949-1961 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Faculty luncheons, 1956-1969 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Faculty-student Forum, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Film Program, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Film Series, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Gay Liberation Front, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - International Ministry, 1965-1969 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Law School-Coalition to End the War, [1970] (Box 26, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225044 2
  - Lutheran Foundation, 1957-1977 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Moratorium Day, Oct 15, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - New Communities (Georgia Project), 1972 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - New Future Foundation, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - New University Conference, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - NYU Medical Center (chemical warfare), 1970 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - OASIS (foreign students), 1963-1967 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - PRISM (newsletter), 1964 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Protestants & the counterculture, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Race and the Arts, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Race Relations Series, Summer 1963 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Religious Census, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225045 9
  - Religious Center, Architectural notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Scene, newsletter, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - SCOPE, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - SCLC (Southern Christian Leadership Conference), 1965 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Student Christian Fellowship, 1962-1964 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Student Revolt, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 7)